EUNJEONG LEE

Raleigh, NC 27613 | Phone:919-916-7239 | Email: ejlee127@gmail.com

Homepage: https://ejlee127.github.io

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ejlee127, GitHub: https://github.com/ejlee127

SUMMARY

Creative, rigorous and systematic data analyst with skills in Python, SQL, JavaScript, Machine Learning and cryptographic algorithms. Earned a certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization from BootCamp of UNC at Chapel Hill, NC. 10+ years of research experience in number theory and cryptography with Ph.D degree in mathematics. Strengths including problem solving abilities combined with collaborating across diverse groups. Enthusiastic for learning novel areas, searching for the hidden skeleton of data and exploring the various ways to find simple and clear solutions.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: Python, C. JavaScript, VBA Tools: Flask API, Spark, Tensorflow, Sklearn

Databases: SQL, MongoDB

Visualization: Tableau, D3, Plotly, ChartJS Mathematics: Magma, Maple, Sage, Latex Cryptography: RSA, ECC, EC-DSA, SHA, MD5

PROJECTS

Patent and TradeMark data collection:

- This project collects the data from the patent documents given as xml files provided by the client (Github link: https://github.com/ejlee127/PatentXmlParsing)
- This project collects the data from the trade mark publications by cURL requests to the USPTO API (Github link: https://github.com/ejlee127/TradeMarkData)
- Tools: Python, xml parsing, cURL, PostgreSQL

Urban Sound Classification using Machine Learning:

Github link: https://github.com/ejlee127/UrbanSoundClassificationUsingML

Deployed page: https://ejlee127.github.io/UrbanSoundML

- This project finds a model to classify the 10 types of sounds using the UrbanSound8K dataset and machine learning algorithms.
- My role was creating the codes for data processing, which extracts the features from audio files
 to construct samples for machine learning algorithms. In addition, storing the samples in
 AWS-RDS(PostgreSQL), creating codes for machine learning process and analyzing the
 experiment results.
- Tools: Python, Matplotlib, Spark, Sklearn, Tensorflow, SQL, AWS S3 and RDS

NC-County Statistics:

Github link: https://github.com/georgealym/project-one
Deployed page: https://guiet-peak-17157.herokuapp.com/

- This project develops a consolidated dashboard of NC county employment statistics for multiple years for each county.
- My role was collecting data from census.gov using API calls, cleaning the data, and developing Flask APIs to retrieve the data. Also, using ChartJS library, I created javascript codes to represent the bar and line charts.
- Tools: Python, Flask API, MongoDB, JavaScript, Bootstrap, D3, Leaflet, CSS, ChartJS

Soccer Home Advantage Analysis | Github link: https://github.com/georgealym/project-one

- This project reviews the international soccer data in the European league to check the common assumption home team has advantage is real.
- My role was collecting attendance data (csv, api), creating python codes for data cleaning and analyzing the relation between the attendance and the scores.
- Tools: Python, Matplotlib

EXPERIENCE

Visiting Scholar

2014 - 2015

Dept. of Mathematics, NCSU

Raleigh, NC

- Performed joint research on number theory problems with Professor Hoon Hong.
- Served as an external member on a doctoral dissertation committee for two doctoral candidates
- Tools : Maple (algebraic mathematical package), Latex.

Key Accomplishments:

One peer reviewed journal paper (Journal of Number Theory) and 2 technical reports

Research Professor 2010 – 2014

Ewha Institute of Mathematical Sciences

Seoul. South Korea

- Led the research projects about Algorithms in Cryptography.
- Taught the classes on cryptography for undergraduate and graduate students.
- Served as a referee for the publications of research articles submitted to AsiaCrypt, ICISC, SCN, Systems & Software, and Human Tech Thesis Prize, etc.

Key Accomplishments:

- 7+ peer reviewed paper publications in number theory and cryptography journals such as Finite Fields and Their Applications, Journal of Number Theory and Design, Codes and Cryptography
- PI of the grant Basic Science Research Program (2011-2014)

EDUCATION

Data Analytics and Visualization Certificate: BootCamp of University of North Carolina at ChapelHill A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

Ph.D in Mathematics: POSTECH, South Korea majored in Mathematics

Dissertation: Computation of Tate pairing on hyperelliptic curves and its applications - developing algorithms for the efficient Tate pairing-based cryptosystem, proposing a key agreement protocol as an application, and analyzing the efficiency by implementing the algorithms in C

VOLUNTEER

CLI Prison Alliance: helping with the hands-on tasks of prison ministry i(2017 ~)

Ladies Bible Study Group: leading a ladies' group to help the members stay connected and encourage each other (2018 \sim)

Music arrangement: providing music scores for a teens' music ensemble according to their level and instruments (2019 ~)